<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD Simplified DocBook XML V1.2CR1//EN"
    "http://docbook.org/xml/simple/1.2CR1/sdocbook.dtd">

<article lang="en">
<title>Dlcounter_XH Manual</title>
<articleinfo>
<author><firstname>Christoph</firstname><surname>Becker</surname><othername>M.</othername></author>
</articleinfo>
<abstract>
<para> Dlcounter_XH is a simple download counter for CMSimple_XH. Instead of a
link to the downloadable file, it offers the downloads as HTML form, which
should be ignored by bots, so the download count is somewhat more accurate.
Please note that absolute accurate download counts cannot be archieved with
Dlcounter_XH (and probably neither with any other download counter) as e.g.
cancelled downloads or multiple downloads initiated by download managers are not
especially catered for. The downloads statistics can be accessed in the plugins
back-end. </para>
</abstract>

<section id="important-notice">
<title>Important Notice</title>
<para>Dlcounter_XH couldn't be tested so far in various environments and it's
quite likely that some features may change (particularly the statistics in the
back-end). It is a so called ALPHA version. <emphasis>Use with
caution!</emphasis></para>
</section>

<section id="requirements">
<title>Requirements</title>
<para>Dlcounter_XH is a plugin for CMSimple_XH ≥ 1.2. It requires a UTF-8
encoded version and <ulink
url="http://www.cmsimple-xh.com/wiki/doku.php/plugins:jquery4cmsimple">jQuery4CMSimple</ulink>.</para>
</section>

<section id="installation">
<title>Installation</title>
<para>The installation is done as with many other CMSimple_XH plugins. See the
<ulink
url="http://www.cmsimple-xh.com/wiki/doku.php/manuals:users_manual:plugins:installation">CMSimple_XH
wiki</ulink> for further details.</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>Backup the data on your server.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Unzip the distribution on your computer.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Upload the whole directory dlcounter/ to your server into
CMSimple_XH's plugins directory.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Set write permissions to the subdirectories config/, css/,
languages/ and the plugin's data folder.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Protect Dlcounter_XH's data and downloads folder against direct
access by any means your webserver provides. An .htaccess file for Apache
servers is already distributed in the default data folder.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Switch to "Dlcounter" in the back-end to check if all
requirements are fulfilled.</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>

<section id="settings">
<title>Settings</title>
<para>The plugin's configuration is done as with many other CMSimple_XH plugins
in the website's back-end. Select "Dlcounter" from "Plugins".</para>
<para>You can change the default settings of Dlcounter_XH in "Plugin Config".
Hints for the options will be displayed when hovering over the help icon with
your mouse.</para>
<para>Localization is done in "Plugin Language". You can translate the character
strings to your own language, or customize them according to your needs.</para>
<para>The look of Dlcounter_XH can be customized in "Plugin Stylesheet". Please
note, that the statistics view in the back-end is quite likely to change in the
next release, so don't spend much time on customizing it's look.</para>
</section>

<section id="usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>All downloads that shall be counted, have to placed in the configured
downloads folder or a subfolder thereof. To display the download form for the
file <literal>download.pdf</literal> on a page, enter:</para>
<programlisting>{{{PLUGIN:dlcounter('download.pdf');}}}</programlisting>
<para>You can safely check, if the download works as expected, by triggering it
when your logged in as administrator; these downloads will not be counted. If
you like to use another PNG graphic for the download button, you can exchange
the default one in the plugin's images/ folder. There are aleady some
alternatives with different color schemes.</para>
<para>To view the download statistics just switch to
"Plugins→Dlcounter→Statistics". You can sort the tables by clicking on the
respective column heading.</para>
</section>

<section id="license">
<title>License</title>
<para>Dlcounter_XH is licensed under GPLv3.</para>
<para>© 2012 Christoph M. Becker</para>
</section>

<section id="credits">
<title>Credits</title>
<para>Dlcounter_XH uses the <ulink url="http://tablesorter.com/">jQuery
Tablesorter plugin</ulink>. Many thanks to Christian Bach for releasing it under
GPL.</para>
<para>The plugin icon is designed by <ulink
url="http://yellowicon.com/">YellowIcon</ulink>. Many thanks for releasing this
icon under GPL.</para>
<para>The downloads buttons are designed by <ulink
url="http://www.graphicsfuel.com/about-me/">Rafi</ulink>. Many thanks for
releasing them as freeware.</para>
<para>This plugin uses free applications icons from <ulink
url="http://www.aha-soft.com/">Aha-Soft</ulink>. Many thanks for making these
icons freely available.</para>
<para>And last but not least many thanks to <ulink
url="http://www.harteg.dk/">Peter Harteg</ulink>, the "father" of CMSimple, and
all developers of <ulink url="http://www.cmsimple-xh.com/">CMSimple_XH</ulink>
without whom this amazing CMS wouldn't exist.</para>
</section>

</article>
